The technology that connects us also controls us.
The Social Dilemma is a documentary, drama film directed by Jeff Orlowski.
This documentary-drama hybrid explores the dangerous human impact of social
networking, with tech experts sounding the alarm on their own creations.
Self, played by Tristan Harris.
Self, played by Jeff Seibert.
Self, played by Bailey Richardson.
Self, played by Joe Toscano.
Self, played by Sandy Parakilas.
Self, played by Guillaume Chaslot.
The Social Dilemma is a 2020 American docudrama film directed by Jeff
Orlowski and written by Orlowski, Davis Coombe, and Vickie Curtis.
The documentary covers the negative social effects of social media and is interspersed by a dramatized
narrative surrounding a family of five who are increasingly affected by problematic social media use.
The Social Dilemma premiered at the 2020 Sundance Film Festival, on January 26, 2020, and
was released on Netflix on September 9, 2020, during the COVID-19 pandemic.
It received mostly positive reviews from critics, who praised its message and use of interviews with established
tech experts but criticized the narrative and lack of nuance in addressing technological problems.
The film explores themes of artificial intelligence (a.i.),
technology, silicon valley, high tech surveillance, internet.
The tone is emotional.